American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 2, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Orders copy of Transactions, vol. 17.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 5, 1895; 5x8; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends price of Transactions, vol. 18.
  - Letter to [George Henry Horn?], Oct. 5, 1895; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, [Germany], A.L.S. 1p., and end. Enc. wanting. Sends paper on Apatela for Proceedings. Sends his photograph. Describes his work at the Roemer Museum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 388-392.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 12, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Arnold, Edward, bookseller
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks price of various issues of proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 15, 1895; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Meacham, Frank Adams, 1862-1902
    Salt Lake City, Utah, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends payment for Proceedings, No. 145.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, Oct. 17, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Asks for copies of new by-laws.
  - Receipt No.298 for a collection of coins and medals of the A.P.S., deposited on loan...as see annexed list, Oct. 22, 1895; 14-1/2x5; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., Printed form filled in in MS., S.: Dalton Dorr 2p. For list, see Pennsylvania museum. List of coins and medals...[April 3, 1896]
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Oct. 23, 1895; 8x5, 3x6; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. and envelope Nearly finished with description of A.P.S. numismatic collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 23, 1895; 10-1/2x8; San Domingo Improvement Company (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, Typed L.S.: E. D. York, Secy. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Gabb's Topography and geography of Santo Domingo.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 24, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Robins, James W.
    [Merion Station], A.N. in 3d person 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to George R. [sic] Horn, Oct. 26, 1895; 8x5; Cassatt, A. J. (Alexander Johnston), 1839-1906
    Haverford, Pa., L.S. 2p. and end. Cannot prepare an obituary of H.H. Houston.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], Oct. 26, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Estoclet, A.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about "A Letter from Mr. Otto to Dr. Franklin, with a Memoir on the Discovery of America," in A.P.S. Transactions, o.s., vol. 2, pp. 263-284.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 31, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Harper, Francis P. (Francis Perego), 1856?-1932
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Asks to make copy of Thomas Sullivan's Revolutionary War journal, with eye to publication. Refers to Coues' edition of the Lewis and Clark journals. Sends set of Coues' edition of Pike's expedition.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 31, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Kelly, James, bookseller
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Orders Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Statement of charges due from the American philosophical society, Nov. 1, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Electro-Tint Engraving Co.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, Nov. 1, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art.
    Phila,, A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Sending catalogue by messenger.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, Nov. 5, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 2p. Transfer of A.P.S. numismatic collection to Museum nearly completed.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 5, 1895; 10x8; United States. Dept. of Agriculture
    Washington, Typed L.S.: W. P. Cutter, Librarian. 2p., end. Asks for issues of Proceedings lacking in file given them by C.V. Riley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 7, 1895; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Eigenmann, Carl H., 1863-1927
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p., end. Purchase of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 7, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Kelly, James, bookseller
    New York, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns order for Transactions. Refers to British Museum.
  - Receipt to James Kelley [sic], Nov. 9, 1895; United States Express Company.
    T.D. Mss filled in.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Nov. 11, 1895; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.] L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copies of membership list.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Nov. 12, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p., end. Hopes to add C. Biddle and M. Sulzberger to Phillips prize committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 15, 1895; 7x4-1/2; Pepper, Edward, 1847-1913
    El-Afia El-Biar, Algeria, A.L.S. 2p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends receipt for Proceedings, No. 147, and his photograph.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 20, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends remittance.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Nov. 22, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Is sending MS. of his paper, "Jasper and stalagmite quarried by Indians in the Wyandotte Cave." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 396-400.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1895; 10-1/2x7-1/2; Yonkers Historical and Library Association
    Yonkers, N.Y., Printed L. filled in in MS., and S.: William E. Ketcham 1p., end. Asks for A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Nov. 25, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], Concerns a circular and the election of members. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 26, 1895; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Clarke, Thomas Curtis, 1827-1901
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Nov. 26, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Asks for copy of A.P.S. regulations. Inquires about rules for elections of officers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 27, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns cost of plates for two papers.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic], Nov. 27, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Returns mailing list. Gives address of G. Harding. Refers to H.E. Lehman.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Nov. 29, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 3p., end. Concerns form of notices of next meeting, qualifications for voting, and preparation of a list of qualified voters. Discusses [P. Frazer's?] candidacy for office of secretary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 4, 1895; 7x4-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Chooses Kendall, Lesley and Brinton for Vice-Presidents.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 4, 1895; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Friebis, George, 1847?-1912
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p., end. Lists his choices for Vice-president: Brinton, Barker and Tatham.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 4, 1895; 10-1/2x8; James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925
    Phila., Typed L.S., with MS. additions 1p., end. Concerns a pamphlet on proportional representation, which he wishes printed in the Proceedings. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 468-471.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Dec. 10, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Enc. wanting Sends invitation to private view of coin collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 11, 1895; 8X5; Arnold, Edward, bookseller
    London, L. 1p., end. Sending draft.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Dec. 11, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Pleased to learn A.P.S. will deposit numismatic collection at Museum.
  - List of medals deposited at the Pennsylvania Musuem, Dec. 15, 1895; 9x6; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    D. 1p., end.: Received above from Dr. Morris... [S.:] Dalton Dorr
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Dec. 16, 1895; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, [Germany], A.L.S. 2p., end. Refers to Phillips' death. Asks for assistance in getting his paper on moths printed. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 416-436.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 19, 1895; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Palmer, T. S. (Theodore Sherman), 1868-1955
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Proceedings, No. 147.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Dec. 20, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: F. D. Langenheim 1p. Will report on items missing from A.P.S. numismatic collection in January. Refers to Dalton Dorr.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Dec. 21, 1895; 9-1/2x6; Georgia Historical Society
    Savannah, Ga., A.L.S.: W[illa]m Harden, Librarian 2p., end. Thanks for prompt reply and assistance. Regrets Phillips death.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 21, 1895; 7-3/4x5; Palmer, T. S. (Theodore Sherman), 1868-1955
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends payment for Proceedings, No. 147.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 23, 1895; 11x8-1/4; Macmillan & Co.
    New York, L. 2p. Offers to supply English publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 24, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Arnold, Edward, bookseller
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Purchase of Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], Dec., 1895; 11x8-3/4; Imperatorskoe russkoe geograficheskoe obshchestvo
    St. Petersburg, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: P. de Semenou 1p. In French. Announces its 50th anniversary.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [1895]; 8-3/4x5-1/4; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for copies of photographs of the Hall.
  - Catalogue of A.P.S. numismatic collection, [1895]; 14x17; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    D. 27p. In three columns Comparison of lists of A.P.S. donations, the receipt of Numismatic and Antiquarian Society, and proposed receipt of Pennsylvania Musuem. Cf. A.P.S. Curatos. Resolution calling for a comparison of various lists... April 30, 1895.
  - Note of introduction for Mr. Dawson, to [Ella M.] Morison, [1895?]; 1-3/4x3-1/2; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    A.N.S. on visiting card 1p.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 2, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Typed L.S. 1p. Copy. Concerns nominations and report of the Secretaries given on Jan. 2, 1896.
  - Letter to Albert S[amuel] Gatschet, Jan. 2, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Copy Concerns C.H. Hart.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 4, 1896; 10-3/4x8; Poole, Murray Edward, b. 1857
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to become member.
  - Letter to W[illiam] B[erryman] Scott, Jan. 5, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. Has his drawings for an unidentified paper.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Jan. 8, 1896; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 1P., end. Appoints Price, Morris and S. Dickson to committee of inquiry.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Jan. 10, 1896; 11-1/4x9; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 1p., end. Refers to his papers on hypenoid moths and on Apatela. Describes work at the Roemer Museum. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 388-392 and pp. 416-136.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Jan. 11, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns A.L. Snowden.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Jan. 13, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Newton, H. A. (Hubert Anson), 1830-1896
    New Haven, Conn., A.L.S. 1p. Has found his copy of the Memorial Volume of the Proceedings, vol. 32.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, 1896; 10-1/2x8; Emmens, Stephen N.
    New Brighton, N.Y., [i.e., 1897]. Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Is sending paper on gravitation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 15, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Drexel Institute of Art, Science and Industry
    Phila., A.L.S.: James MacAlister 1p., end. Asks for copy of Smith's Theory of the state, the Phillips prize essay. For printed essay, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 181-332.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Jan. 15, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Send copies of Phillips prize essay to the judges.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, Jan. 18, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for bound volumes of Proceedings. 1892 and 1893. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Jan. 18, 1896; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Returns bound volumes of Proceedings. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Institute of Mining Engineers
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Returns wrapper received without its contents.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 22, 1896; 8x5; Tucker, John Randolph, 1823-1897
    Lexington, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for copies of Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Jan. 23, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his paper on Old Babylonian inscriptions. Refers to Price. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 221-282.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Jan. 23, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p. Enc. wanting. Sends note from Horn, concerning the preparation of Hilprecht's paper on Old Babylonian inscriptions. Refers to Partridge. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 221-282.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Jan. 23, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Hilprecht's paper on Old Babylonian inscriptions. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 221-282.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Jan. 23, 1896; 9-1/2x5-3/4; University of Virginia
    [Charlottesville, Va.], A.L.S.: H[enry] W[inslow] Page, Librarian 1p., end. Asks for complete set of Proceedings to replace that destroyed by fire.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 29, 1896; 11x8; Smith, George H.
    Los Angeles, Cal., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his Theory of the state, the Phillips prize essay. For printed essay, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 181-332.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Jan. 30, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Green, Samuel A. (Samuel Abbott), 1830-1918
    Boston, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns order for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [George Leonard Vose], Jan. 31, 1896; 9x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.: Ella Morison, Assnt. Librarian 1p., end.. by Vose. Inquires about payment for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 31, 1896; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks for copies of the plate for his paper [on Cotylosauria?], for notice in The American Naturalist.
  - Letter to Henry C[hapman] Mercer, Feb. 2, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. corrections 1p. Copy Concerns Mercer's talk on fossil sloth. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 3, 1896; 10-1/2x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Benj[amin] Sharp, Corresponding Secretary 1p. Requests permission for microscopic examination of jade on deposit at Academy.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 3, 1896; 10-1/2x8; Kephart, Samuel A.
    Fort Monroe, Va. A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copies of essays which won the Henry M. Phillips Prize.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Feb. 6, 1896; 7-3/4x6; Hailty, Henry
    Vicksburg, Miss., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his self-nomination for membership.
  - Receipts, Feb. 17, 1896 - June 23, 1897; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    6 receipts
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 19, 1896; 3-1/4 x5-1/4; Arnold, Edward, bookseller
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Feb. 19, 1896; 11x8-1/2; James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 20, 1896; 9x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., [i.e., 1897] A.L.S.: W[illia]m A. Pickell, Secretary 3p. Concerns complaint about cost of printing.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 25, 1896; 7x4-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p. Discusses his question about eligibility of candidates and voters. See A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 35, pp. 3, 5.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Feb. 27, 1896; 9-1/2x6; University of Vermont
    Burlington, Vt., A.L.S.: Thomas R. Barnum, Librarian 1p., end. Asks for publications.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, March 5, 1896; 8x5; Harvard University. Museum of Comparative Zoology
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S.: H. S. Clark 1p., end. Concerns Proceedings and J.D. Whitney.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 6, 1896; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Canada. Dept. of Justice
    Ottawa, Typed L.S.: Lawrence J[ohnstone] Burpee, Secretary. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], March 7, 1896; 8x4-3/4; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends pamphlet.
  - Jubilee of the Right Honourable Professor Lord Kelvin, March 10, 1896; 15x11-1/4; University of Glasgow
    Glasgow, Printed D. 1p.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, March 10, [1896]; 9x5-3/4; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns paper by E. Pepper on the Eucalyptus. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 35-56.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, March 11, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Enc. Sends Receipt No.304 for A.P.S. numismatic collection. For receipt, see Pennsylvania museum. Receipt No.304...March 11, 1896.
  - List of medals and plaster casts of medals, deposited by the A.P.S., under Receipt No.304 (R.2), March 11, 1896; 13x8; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    [Phila.] Typed D. with MS. additions, S.: Dalton Dorr 5p. With unsigned copy marked "Duplicate." For receipt, see Pennsylvania museum. Receipt No.304...March 11, 1896.
  - Receipt No. 304 for a collection of 202 medals and plaster casts of medals...described in accompanying list, March 11, 1896; 7x5, 4x8-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., Printed form filled in in MS., S.: Dalton Dorr 2p. and envelope, end. For list, see Pennsylvania museum. List of medals...March 11, 1896.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 12, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Recommends E. Pepper's paper on Eucalyptus for publication in the Proceedings. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 35-56.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, March 14, 1896; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns errata in printing of his paper, "Hypenoid moths and allied groups." Describes work at Roemer Museum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings. vol. 34, pp. 416-436.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, March 14, 1896; 10-3/4x8-1/4; University of Pennsylvania. General Alumni Society
    Phila., A.L.S.: Ewing Jordan 2p. Enc. wanting. Thanks should go to E.P. Cheyney and the Society of the Alumni for enclosed copy of Matriculate Catalogue of the College...1749-1893.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, March 17, 1896; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns copies of his papers for a J. Leed Roberts. Mentions paper on "Ichthyology of the Lesser Antilles", in A.P.S. Transactions, vol. 14, pp. 445-483.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, March 17, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Concerns A.P.S. numismatic collection. Refers to F.D. Langenheim and Library Company.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 20, 1896; 8x5; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Wilkesbarre, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. Inquires about papers of Susqhehanna Co. commissioners. Refers to J.B. Gibson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 20, 1896; 6-1/4x5-1/4; Liston, Jennie E.
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks to become a member. Written on verso is copy of Frazer's reply. See Frazer to Litson, March 22, 1896.
  - Letter to [Jennie E. Litson; Phila.], March 22, 1896; 6-1/4x5-1/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.S. 1p. Copy. Gives rules for becoming a member. Written on verso of Litson to the A.P.S., March 20, 1896.
  - Letter to [Joseph George] Rosengarten, March 22, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Wallingford, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Will supply Gutekunst photographs of his father, W.H. Furness, for obituary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 23, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Brown University
    Providence, R.I., A.L. on postal card. S.: H[arry] L[yman] Koopman, Librarian 1p., end., and add. Asks price of proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 23, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, L.S.: N. Murray, Librarian 1p., end. Asks about Transactions.
  - Letter to E[lla M.] Morison, March 23, 1896; 9x6; United States. Dept. of Agriculture
    Washington, A.L.S.: Henry E[lijah] Alvord 1p., end. Concerns recent pamphlet on the milk supply of cities, by G.M. Whitaker.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, March 24, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Concerns transfer of Library Company's medals to Museum. Refers to F.D. Langenheim, J.G. Barnwell.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, March 24, 1896; 8-1/4x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends H.H. Furness's note about photograph of his father, W.H. Furness, for his obituary. Refers to Sachse. For enclosure, see H.H. Furness to Rosengarten, March 20, 1896.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 25, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Suomen Maantieteellinen Seura
    Helsinki, A.L. on postal card, S.: Charles Moberg. 1p., end., and add. In French. Exchange of Publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Barnes, Parker Thayer, b. 1874
    Geneva, N.Y., A.L.S. 1P., end. Orders Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Brown University
    Providence, R.I., A.L. on postal card, S.: H[arry] L[yman] Koopman, Librarian. 1p., end., and add. Orders issues of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1896; 9x5-1/2; Cornell University
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S.: Geo[rge] W[illia]m Harris, Librarian 1p., end. Purchase of Transactions.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, March 26, 1896; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p., end. Appoints R.S. Hunter to prepare obituary of Henry Reed. Refers to obituary of O.J. Wister, Henry Phillips.